Jiecheng Luo

Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, University College London 1-19 Torrington Place, London, WC1E 7HB jiecheng.luo.20@ucl.ac.uk

+44 (0) 7410 937 710

I'm a self-motivated PhD student who has developed research quantitative and analytical skills with a strong capacity to conduct independent research. I am interested in developing a career that combines teaching and research, while maintaining my interest in public engagement on ageing into disability.

Educations

University College London (2020-present, UK), PhD student

- Enrolled in the PhD programme of Epidemiology and Public Health.
- Self-funded research project titled 'Association between physical functioning and social relationships among older adults in China'.
- Joint supervisors: Professor Anne McMunn and Dr Baowen Xue, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, UCL.

Xiamen University (2017-2020, China), Master of Public Health

- Core modules included: Advanced Health Statistics, Advanced Epidemiology and Senior Health Service Management.
- Final-year dissertation on 'Heterogeneous health groups and healthcare utilization among older adults in China' based on research carried out on the Chinese Longitudinal Healthy Longevity Survey.

Anhui Medical University (2012-2017, China), Bachelor of Management

- Major in Public Service Administration, concentration in Healthcare Management.
- Core modules included: Social Medicine, Epidemiology, Health Statistics, Health Economics, Leadership Science, and Healthcare Management.
- One-year training on Clinical Medicine.

Teaching Experiences

PGTA, Global Business School for Health UCL (Sep 2022- July 2023)

- Modules: Leadership and Management in Global Healthcare (GBSH0010) and Changing Health Systems (GBSH0007).
- Delivering weekly teaching session and organising group discussion in class.
- Marking and writing feedback.

Training Assistant, Information Services Division UCL (Sep 2021-present)

- Module: Digital Skills Development, mainly in section 'An Introduction to R with Rstudio'.
- Helped the trainers during training sessions and group discussions.
- Assisted students with practical tasks.

PGTA, Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health UCL (Jan 2022- July 2022)

- Modules: Regression modelling, Health Inequalities over the Lifecourse.
- Hosted online sessions on Zoom.
- Marking and writing feedback.

Teaching Assistant, Xiamen University (Jul 2018-Aug 2018)

- Module: Big data mining technology in health care.
- Pre-preparation before teaching sessions.
- Monitor attendance.
- Marking and writing assessment.

Skills

- Analysis and mathematical modelling in R and SPSS.
- Leadership and Management.
- Photography.

Publications

- Ye L, **Luo J**, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Multidimensional Health Groups and Healthcare Utilization Among Elderly Chinese: Based on the 2014 CLHLS Dataset. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2019;16(20):3884. doi:10.3390/ijerph16203884
- Zeng Y, Luo J, Ou L, et al. The impact of medical insurance on medical expenses for older Chinese: Evidence from the national baseline survey of CLHLS. Medicine. 2019;98(39):e17302. doi:10.1097/MD.00000000017302
- Ye L, **Luo J**, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Heterogeneous health classes for older adults and their regional disparities in China: based on multidimensional health. Public Health. 2020;178:15-22. doi:10.1016/j.puhe.2019.08.023

Conferences

- The Aging & Public Health program of the American Public Health Association's 2019 Annual Meeting and Expo.
- The Gerontological Society of America's 71st Annual Scientific Meeting.

References

Professor Anne McMunn - University College London, a.mcmunn@ucl.ac.uk

Professor Yae - University College London, baowen.xue.10@ucl.ac.uk

Professor Yae Fang - Xiamen University, fangya@xmu.edu.cn